A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Scientific Reports of the Laboratories to the Corporation and to the Board of Scientific Directors FA145
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Scientific Reports of the Laboratories to the Corporation and to the Board of Scientific Directors
1901-1955
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Rockefeller University
Gasser, Herbert S. (Herbert Spencer)
FA145
10.6 Cubic Feet 24 document boxes.
24 document boxes consisting of 42 volumes and several additional reports.
Scope and Contents note
Consists of reports on work done in the laboratories, hospital, Department of Animal and Plant Pathology; under grants to Babies' Hospital; War Demonstration Hospital. Reports made to the Scientific Directors at April or May meetings (early reports made more frequently) and to the Corporation at meetings held in October. Included as addenda are some special reports and copies of letters.
Some special reports of the Director of the Institute to the Corporation are included.
1955 volume is incomplete.
Starting v. 15 (1926/1927) reports to the Corporation are topical narratives on selected work; with v. 24 (1935/1936) the reports to the Corporation consists of fully treated selected subjects. With v. 39 (1950/1951) presentation of reports to the Scientific Directors follows new organization of divisions in the Departments and reflects unification of Princeton and New York City laboratories. The reports to the Corporation are from the Directors and are in skeletal form giving an overall picture of investigations in progress.
No scientific reports were made to the Corporation in v. 23 (1934/1935) or in v. 41 (1953) because of the change in the Directorship of the Institute in those years. Volume 42 (1953/1954) is a general scientific report to the Board of Trustees reflecting the change in organization. 1955 was never presented and is incomplete.
Arrangement note
Arranged in chronological order.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 439
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Many of the volumes of scientific reports are in poor or brittle condition.
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for scholarly research.
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Existence and Location of Copies
A complete set of all 42 volumes of scientific reports is also available at the Campus Office of the Rockefeller University Archives.
Trypanosomiasis; Tryparsamide; African trypanosomiasis; Pathology; World War I; Hospitals; Diseases; Medical research; Medical education; Medical sciences; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; Rockefeller University; Rockefeller Institute Hospital. (Compiègne, France); Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research. War Demonstration Hospital; Gasser, Herbert S. (Herbert Spencer)
- 1902 April-1908 October (Box 1, Folder 1, Volume 1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  This collection is open for scholarly research.
  Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
- 1909 January-1911 October (Box 1, Folder 2, Volume 2)
- 1912 January-1914 October (Box 1, Folder 3, Volume 3)
  - Report to the Trustees of The RIMR by the Scientific Directors on the Establishment of New Activities for the Promotion of Public Health., 1914 October
    Scope and Contents
    A Summary accompanies report.
- 1915 January-1916 October (Box 2, Folder 1, Volume 4)
- 1917 January-October (Box 2, Folder 2, Volume 5)
  Photocopying is not permitted.
  - Report on the Hospital at Compiègne, 1917
- 1918 January-October (Box 3, Folder 1, Volume 6)
  - Report on War Activities; Outline of Instruction War Demonstration Hospital, 1918
- 1919 January-October (Box 3, Folder 2, Volume 7)
  - Report on War activities with Addenda, 1919
    Addenda includes: copies of letters of appreciation of contributions and work of The Rockefeller Institute.
- 1920 January-October (Box 3, Folder 3, Volume 8)
  Includes Addendum: (1) Letter from Louise Pearce on African Expedition (2) Special report from Simon Flexner and one from A. E. Cohn on trip abroad in relation to special Institute problems in physiology and pharmacology. Positions offered to Hoguchi, Van Slyke, Swift and Blake.
- 1921 January-October (Box 4, Folder 1, Volume 9)
- 1922 January-October (Box 4, Folder 2, Volume 10)
  Includes Appendix: Abstract of paper by E.J. Butler, read before The Royal Society of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene.
- 1922-1923 (Box 5, Folder 1, Volume 11)
  Work at Babies' hospital under Institute grant brought to a close, 1923. Includes complete list of publications done under grants.
- 1923 October-1924 October (Box 5, Folder 2, Volume 12)
  Includes work done on grant to J.W. Gowen.
  Includes work done on grant to Lionell C. Strong.
  Report on status of Tryparsamide investigations including copies of letters from researchers using the material.
- 1924 October-1925 October (Box 6, Folder 1, Volume 13)
  Includes report of work done on grant to E. V. Cowdry.
  Includes report of work done on grant to W. J. V. Osterhout.
  Report on use of Tryparsamide in paresis and African Sleeping Sickness.
- 1925 October-1926 October (Box 7, Folder 1, Volume 14)
  Includes report from Louise Pearce on status of Tryparsamide treatment for sleeping sickness in the Congo 1926 April 17 presented to Board of Scientific Directors "Developments of the First Twenty Years of the RI and an outlook for Further Growth".
- 1926 October-1927 October (Box 8, Folder 1, Volume 15)
- 1927 October-1928 October (Box 9, Folder 1, Volume 16)
- 1928 October-1929 October (Box 9, Folder 2, Volume 17)
  No scientific report to Corporation. At October 25, 1929 meeting an announcement was made that a 25 year review was in progress and would be mailed.
- 1929 October-1930 October (Box 10, Folder 1, Volume 18)
  Includes Sketch of the First Twenty-Five Years of RIMR (Review by Simon Flexner and presented to the Corporation October 31, 1930).
- 1930 October-1931 October (Box 10, Folder 2, Volume 19)
- 1931 October-1932 October (Box 11, Folder 1, Volume 20)
- 1932 October-1933 October (Box 11, Folder 2, Volume 21)
- 1933 October-1934 October (Box 12, Folder 1, Volume 22)
  Reports to Corporation are abstracts of detailed reports submitted in April to Scientific Directors.
- 1934 October-1935 April (Box 12, Folder 2, Volume 23)
  Corporation reports usually presented in October waived because of change in Directorship.
- 1935 October-1936 October (Box 12, Folder 3, Volume 24)
- 1936 October-1937 October (Box 13, Folder 1, Volume 25)
  Corporation report includes long review articles by P.A.T. Levene and One by Peyton Rous.
- 1937 October-1938 October (Box 13, Folder 2, Volume 26)
  Corporation reports include review articles by M. Bergmann; F. Sabin; P. McMaster and L. Webster.
- 1938 October-1939 October (Box 14, Folder 1, Volume 27)
  Corporation reports include special articles by K. Landsteiner; J. Northrop; A. B. Sabin; L. Webster.
- 1939 October-1940 October (Box 14, Folder 2, Volume 28)
  - Report on the Activities and Problems of The Rockefeller Institute by Herbert Gasser to the Corporation October 3, 1939, 1939 October 3
    Scope and Contents note
    Appendix includes: Tables showing use of Tryparsamide; Table of discovery at RI of some bacteria with date and name of investigator; Table of RI contributions in virus study.
- 1940 October-1941 October (Box 15, Folder 1, Volume 29)
- 1941 October-1942 October (Box 15, Folder 2, Volume 30)
- 1942 October-1943 October (Box 16, Folder 1, Volume 31)
- 1943 October-1944 October (Box 16, Folder 2, Volume 32)
- 1944 October-1945 October (Box 17, Folder 1, Volume 33)
- 1944 October-1945 October (Box 22, Folder 3, Volume 33)
  Existence and Location of Copies
  Second copy.
- 1945 October-1946 October (Box 17, Folder 2, Volume 34)
- 1945 October-1946 October (Box 23, Folder 1, Volume 34)
- 1946 October-1947 October (Box 18, Folder 1, Volume 35)
- 1946 October-1947 October (Box 23, Folder 2, Volume 35)
- 1947 October-1948 October (Box 18, Folder 2, Volume 36)
- 1947 October-1948 October (Box 24, Folder 1, Volume 36)
- 1948 October-1949 October (Box 19, Folder 1, Volume 37)
  Report to the Corporation includes a preamble "Teaching at the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research" with an appendix listing University Positions held by Former Staff Members at RIMR and listing of Visiting Investigators. Also includes a new form of report from the Laboratories to the Corporation.
- 1949 October-1950 October (Box 19, Folder 2, Volume 38)
- 1950 October-1951 October (Box 20, Folder 1, Volume 39)
  Sequence of reports varies from earlier years in accord with revised classifications also followed in Descriptive pamphlet. Report to Corporation is no longer a brief description, but rather a complete listing of work done under various sections.
  Includes memorandum prepared by Herbert Gasser for John D. Rockefeller, Jr. called "Medical Research; a Look Ahead at the RIMR.
- Supplement to the Report of the Members to the Corporation, 1951 October 26; Pamphlet. (Box 20, Folder 2)
- 1951-1952 (Box 20, Folder 3, Volume 40)
- 1952-1953 (Box 21, Folder 1, Volume 41)
- 1953-1954 (Box 21, Folder 2, Volume 42)
- 1955 (Box 22, Folder 1)
- 1955 (Box 22, Folder 2)